<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://cheuksblog.ca/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Cheuk's Blog</title><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/</link><description>Things that I am learning about</description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 13:07:39 -0800</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2018-04-27-managing-a-group-project/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2018-04-27-managing-a-group-project/</link><title>On Managing a Group Project</title><description>The semester ended, and I just finished a reasonably large group project on
Virtual Reality (link here; teaser here). Let's talk about
what I learned.Stay Silent</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-12-19-googletest-tutorial/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-12-19-googletest-tutorial/</link><title>Google Test Basic Tutorial</title><description>GoalThe goal of this tutorial is to get you up and running with Google Test through
the examples given. This will be more of a walkthrough integrating Google Test
into your project.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-05-10-basic-raycasting-tut/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-05-10-basic-raycasting-tut/</link><title>Basic Raycasting Tutorial</title><description>GoalThis tutorial's goal is to get you acquainted with the idea of ray casting. We
will focus on the most basic method for ray casting: using a combination of unit
vectors, vector addition, and lots and lots of iteration. Sounds fun? Let's dive
in.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-05/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-05/</link><title>Huffman Tutorial Part 5</title><description>If you have arrived at this point, it is assumed that you have slaved through
the parts previous to this one in the series. You may have spent a lot of time -
ranging from a week to half a month - on this (rather large) endeavor. And if
you have made it through, :confetti_ball: CONGRATULATIONS :confetti_ball:!
Good work. Now, here is a way to test that your encoder works: by decoding it!Quick Run-Down of How it Works</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-04-17-tbasic-timeline/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-04-17-tbasic-timeline/</link><title>Tiny BASIC Development - Timeline</title><description>Day 1</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-28-arch-d3/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-28-arch-d3/</link><title>Arch Linux Day 3: Switching Over to i3</title><description>So for some reason or another, I decided that it was a cool idea to switch from
GNOME display manager to the i3 window manager. Well, why not?Installation</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-10-chip8-great-mate/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-10-chip8-great-mate/</link><title>Chip-8 is Great, Mate!</title><description>Rhyming scheme aside, I'm finally somewhat finished the Chip-8 emulator package
that I was working on. Interested people can find the code here. This
includes:</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-07-06-screen-rest/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-07-06-screen-rest/</link><title>screen_rest: The Simplest Passive Program to Get Off the Computer</title><description>The program that I've been waiting for, has now come/been made!For the past ... years, my dad has been telling me that after every hour I'm on
the computer, I should commit 15 minutes to doing something else strictly
NOT computer related. I now have finally created a program to help me:
screen_rest.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-06-22-end-of-school/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-06-22-end-of-school/</link><title>The End of School</title><description>So here I am again, at the end of the school year. Well, almost the end - I
still have a public exam and still have to grab my report card, but at least all
the classes are over. With the end of the academic year, I can finally focus
full force on a lot more of my side projects, as well as some of my "online"
courses. As of writing, I am currently enrolled in a Coursera Android
class. The end of school also means that I could spend time honing my formerly
non-existent chess skills. Mind you, I still need to study for the exam, but
after that, I am/will be in full control for 2 months, right up till school
starts again in September.A (programming) project that I am currently working on is a Chip-8
Emulator. I have expanded it to a Chip-8 toolset, and am currently working
on the assembler. (Any feedback or suggestions are welcome.) The going is quite
slow, because of a small amount of procrastination. And studying.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-04-03-lightning-theory/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-04-03-lightning-theory/</link><title>Basic Lightning Theory</title><description>IntroductionEvery good game needs good visual effects. Here is how to do basic lightning.
This only covers 2D lightning, but you could easily extend this to 3D.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-23-fun-with-qbasic/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-23-fun-with-qbasic/</link><title>Fun with QBasic</title><description>So I had a rough day with windows (I can no longer use it without safe mode,
would fix later), so I wanted to have some fun, so I went with a qbasic tutorial
and made this colorful thing:</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-01-ncurses-editor-tutorial-01/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-01-ncurses-editor-tutorial-01/</link><title>NCURSES Terminal Text Editor Tutorial Part 1</title><description>IntroductionI am using vim right now, and a few days ago, I thought to myself:</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>