<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://cheuksblog.ca/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Cheuk's Blog</title><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/</link><description>Things that I am learning about</description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 13:16:15 -0800</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2021-04-07-lambda-angstrom2021/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2021-04-07-lambda-angstrom2021/</link><title>lambda lambda - angstrom 2021</title><description>lambda lambda [rev 130 points]lambda lambda lambda.... lambda?2692665569775536810618960607010822800159298089096272924hint: Ever hear about lambda calculus?With my 2 semesters worth of experience in programming languages and compiler construction in Racket, I
thought I had the necessary skills to take this on. Here are the 2 approaches I took:</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2020-05-26-timed-tjctf/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2020-05-26-timed-tjctf/</link><title>Timed - tjctf</title><description>This one is a cool blacklist bypass. It's pretty simple. You are presented a
text interface asking you to enter a python command.</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2020-05-08-gradescope-hw-exploits/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2020-05-08-gradescope-hw-exploits/</link><title>Taking advantage of output dumping for a Gradescope programming assignment</title><description>An old story I've been saving up.So I submitted my CS 221 Intro to Data Structures and Algorithms programming
assignment and found something very peculiar. I couldn't figure out why one of
the tests were failing. The test in question was one of those private tests
that students don't have access to, to prevent students from simply outputting
the solution when given a certain input. And to that, I was also pretty sure
that I had followed the assignment to the tee. And thus I wanted to find out
what was the exact input to the test. Luckily for me, the designer for this
assignment left out a point to exploit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2020-03-18-gstreamer-tricks/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2020-03-18-gstreamer-tricks/</link><title>gstreamer tips and tricks</title><description>Streaming video from internet to /dev/video0For cases where you want to use your desktop to do face-to-face meetings with
others but don't want to go out and buy a webcam, this is for you.</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2020-01-08-the-prophet-tetctf/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2020-01-08-the-prophet-tetctf/</link><title>The Prophet - TetCTF</title><description>This was a fun one. We start off with a web page and get a foothold with an
arbitrary file read vulnerability, and end it off with a Python Flask Arbitrary
Code Execution in the web debugger.On the webpage, we are presented with a hyperlink with the text Read some oracle here. Clicking the hyperlink brings us to 5 web pages
/read/oracle/[1-5].txt. One of them, 1.txt, says the following:</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2019-12-31-where-go-infernoctf/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2019-12-31-where-go-infernoctf/</link><title>Where did he GO? - Inferno CTF</title><description>This was also one of the easier ones. As you can tell, I'm not that good at
these things. I also have never scripted in go before. Here's what happened.The program asked for a password, and if the password was correct, we would get
a nice success message. Looking into the program, we see that the input is
checked against an obfuscated string of bytes. The input is run through 2
functions:</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2019-12-30-7110-otw-advent2019-ctf/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2019-12-30-7110-otw-advent2019-ctf/</link><title>7110 - OverTheWire Advent 2019 CTF</title><description>This one was one of the easier ones. We are given some .txt files, .csv
files, and a single .h C header file. We see that the .csv files contain
keylogging data, where the first column is a timestamp and the second column is
the key that was pressed. From these .csv files, we are supposed to figure
out what Santa typed.The .csv files correspond to the .txt files (e.g. sms1.csv corresponds to
sms1.txt), and we are supposed to decode sms4.csv. Though we are not
completely sure what the function keys correspond to (i.e. MENU_LEFT,
MENU_RIGHT, MENU_UP, MENU_DOWN), we can still try to decode the file. And
so we write the following Python code:</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2018-12-06-gh-jekyll-plugs/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2018-12-06-gh-jekyll-plugs/</link><title>Github Jekyll Plugins</title><description>Here is a list of jekyll plugins that can be used on Github using the static
site generator Jekyll:</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2018-04-27-managing-a-group-project/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2018-04-27-managing-a-group-project/</link><title>On Managing a Group Project</title><description>The semester ended, and I just finished a reasonably large group project on
Virtual Reality (link here; teaser here). Let's talk about
what I learned.Stay Silent</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-12-19-googletest-tutorial/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-12-19-googletest-tutorial/</link><title>Google Test Basic Tutorial</title><description>GoalThe goal of this tutorial is to get you up and running with Google Test through
the examples given. This will be more of a walkthrough integrating Google Test
into your project.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-08-14-howto-bioperl/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-08-14-howto-bioperl/</link><title>How to Obtain Cropped Nucleotide Sequences and More</title><description>In my opinion, there isn't much documentation on the BioPerl site: just vague
examples and whatnot.Say for instance you want to get the entire nucleotide sequence of a particular
organism, but it must be split up because you only want to deal with the
proteins, and not the entire organism. So less like this:</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-06-28-cw-fire/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-06-28-cw-fire/</link><title>[Writing] Fire</title><description>Cory noticed the ominous black smoke billowing outwards, and decided to run to
safety. Sadly, his friends had other ideas."This will look great as my profile picture!" Dave smiled.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-05-10-basic-raycasting-tut/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2017-05-10-basic-raycasting-tut/</link><title>Basic Raycasting Tutorial</title><description>GoalThis tutorial's goal is to get you acquainted with the idea of ray casting. We
will focus on the most basic method for ray casting: using a combination of unit
vectors, vector addition, and lots and lots of iteration. Sounds fun? Let's dive
in.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-00/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-00/</link><title>Huffman Tutorial Part 0</title><description>IntroductionAre you curious in how compression systems work? Do you want to know how to
compress and decompress files? Has your high school teacher assigned you the
oh-so-complicated Huffman compression project? If you answer yes to any of these
questions, good for you!</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-03/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-03/</link><title>Huffman Tutorial Part 3</title><description>In this part, we'll figure out how to sketch headers for your Huffman
program!Huffman Headers</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-05/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-05/</link><title>Huffman Tutorial Part 5</title><description>If you have arrived at this point, it is assumed that you have slaved through
the parts previous to this one in the series. You may have spent a lot of time -
ranging from a week to half a month - on this (rather large) endeavor. And if
you have made it through, :confetti_ball: CONGRATULATIONS :confetti_ball:!
Good work. Now, here is a way to test that your encoder works: by decoding it!Quick Run-Down of How it Works</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-02/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-02/</link><title>Huffman Tutorial Part 2</title><description>What we are trying to do, is to take the character frequencies of the file, and
convert all of it into an easily traversable tree to look things up quickly.
Then, we are going to go through the whole tree, and construct a map to map
every character to a string of binary digits.Character Frequencies</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-01/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-01/</link><title>Huffman Tutorial Part 1</title><description>SetupLet's start off with a basic setup, which includes a nice directory structure
and a neat Makefile. What are you looking at me for? Alright, here is my
setup:</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-04/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-07-05-huffman-tutorial-04/</link><title>Huffman Tutorial Part 4</title><description>Ah! Here is the fun part! Actually writing each individual bit into a file! So,
how does one go about doing it?You Don't</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-04-17-tbasic-timeline/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-04-17-tbasic-timeline/</link><title>Tiny BASIC Development - Timeline</title><description>Day 1</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-01-15-arch-d4/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2016-01-15-arch-d4/</link><title>Arch Linux Day 4: Switching Over to neovim</title><description>As if changing over to i3 window manager wasn't enough, I decided to change my
default editor from vim to neovim. Of course, some things may
break (which they did).Installing neovim</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-28-arch-d3/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-28-arch-d3/</link><title>Arch Linux Day 3: Switching Over to i3</title><description>So for some reason or another, I decided that it was a cool idea to switch from
GNOME display manager to the i3 window manager. Well, why not?Installation</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-15-arch-d2/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-15-arch-d2/</link><title>Arch Linux Day 2: Setting up GNOME</title><description>For this day, I didn't read up on any tutorials or guides. I just followed the
instructions from this video: From Post Install to Xorg. As a
result, the rest of this post will mostly be me trying to transcribe the video
into written (typed) words.Software Installations</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-12-arch-d1/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-12-arch-d1/</link><title>Arch Linux Day 1: Installation</title><description>DisclaimerThis is by no means a tutorial or a guide to installing Arch Linux - it is just
how I did my things. Everything that I do should be taken as (at the most)
advice. Everything written here should be taken with a grain of salt, as I am
going off of my memory of what I have done, and may have forgotten things, even
if it was only a few days since I have actually done the deed. I don't remember
every command that I execute.</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-09-arch-d0/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-12-09-arch-d0/</link><title>Arch Linux Day 0: Fact-Checking</title><description>PrefaceA few days ago, I was upgrading my Fedora 20 to Fedora 21 as Fedora 20 wasn't
supported. I finished my upgrade and rebooted my computer. Unfortunately, the
kernel modules failed to load (for some reason or another), and I was stuck on
the GNOME login screen with no mouse and no keyboard. I then opted for a fresh
Fedora 20 install, but I still thought that it was a bit out of date and there
was going to be not much support coming my way if anything went wrong or awry.
That was when I started to think about Linux distribution alternatives that I
could use.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-11-10-cw-incompetent-misunderstanding/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-11-10-cw-incompetent-misunderstanding/</link><title>[Writing] An Incompetent Misunderstanding</title><description>The waiter put down his sandwich. The customer prodded it with a fork. "It's
bloody cold! You make me wait here for a full hour and I get it cold?!" And the
waiter was apologizing - you could almost see him kneeling on the ground. "I'm
sorry. So sorry sir...." And he was using the situation towards his advantage.
"I have had enough of your shenanigans! Don't expect me to give this place even
an inkling of a positive review!" And with that crude remark, he marched out of
his seat and slammed the door with the finality of a gavel. The waiter's faint
protest dimmed to a murmur: "But I thought you said you wanted cold cuts...."</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-10-08-minor-miracle/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-10-08-minor-miracle/</link><title>[Writing] Minor Miracle</title><description>"Pah!" He spat the mouthful of food out with such momentum that it hit the seat
in front of him. He didn't expect the burrito to be so spicy, and was now
gurgling his mouth with water, which didn't seem too effective. He gave what was
left of his meal back to the flight attendant, and started cleaning up the mess
that he made. He was so distracted that he zoned out of the conversation."We could play on the slides. That swingset was rusty anyway."</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-09-12-scrabble-strat-staircase/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-09-12-scrabble-strat-staircase/</link><title>Scrabble Tutorial: Strategies - The Staircase</title><description>IntroductionTo use the strategy that results in a nice staircase formation, you will first
need a very strong memory of common and uncommon 2-letter words, 3-letter
words, and sometimes even 4-letter words. This is where you and the opponent
place tiles (that are often offset by 1) above/below each other, resulting in a
game of "whoever gets to the triple-word bonus tile is a winner". This type of
play often results in the 2-pass ending, where both players cannot find a place
to put tiles, and pass as a result of that (See below).</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-23-challenge-e228/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-23-challenge-e228/</link><title>Challenge #228 [Easy] Letters in Alphabetical Order</title><description>So from here on out, I'm going to try and keep up with /r/dailyprogrammer
and do the challenges (, and post solutions and explanations), in order to
document my progress and increase my ability to communicate via writing.</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-20-scrabble-bingos/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-20-scrabble-bingos/</link><title>Scrabble Tutorial: Prefixes and Suffixes - Bingos</title><description>The easier way to create bingos is to save a prefix/suffix and wait until you
could append/prepend it to a word. As you can see, blank tiles are immensely
useful. Say you are currently saving ING. This makes it so that you only need
to make a 4-letter word with the rest of your tiles instead of a 7 letter word.
Common beginnings/endings that are easy to make words with are:</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-17-scrabble-tile-placement-tut/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-17-scrabble-tile-placement-tut/</link><title>Scrabble Tutorial: Tile Placement</title><description>&lt;side-note&gt;I had to learn this myself: Scrabble move notation. Essentially, how it goes is:</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-13-scrabble-2-letter-words/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-13-scrabble-2-letter-words/</link><title>Scrabble Tutorial: 2-Letter Words</title><description>If you know about the 2 letter words, move on. If you don't, MEMORIZE THEM
ALL.2-letter words are very useful if you want to link your tiles with the tiles on
board, and gain a few extra points. It can wreck people who don't know them
(obviously).</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-10-chip8-great-mate/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-08-10-chip8-great-mate/</link><title>Chip-8 is Great, Mate!</title><description>Rhyming scheme aside, I'm finally somewhat finished the Chip-8 emulator package
that I was working on. Interested people can find the code here. This
includes:</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-07-29-why-cursive/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-07-29-why-cursive/</link><title>Why Cursive?</title><description>So, why am I talking about all that cursive stuff that you probably have
forgotten half of after primary/elementary school?Remember the time when those teachers taught us cursive writing, and told us all
to go buy and do copybooks? When they told us all that the curvy letters would
be mandatory for anyone wishing to pursue higher education? As soon as you hit
high school, you realize that the teachers there don't actually care if you use
it or not, as long as they can read it. Let that sink in and let's move on....</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-07-10-childhood-breakup/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-07-10-childhood-breakup/</link><title>[Writing] Childhood Breakup</title><description>"Hey dearest, come here for a second," my mom beckoned me. Honestly, I was
fairly annoyed, given that I was in the middle of a gym battle, but I came
anyway."Yeah mom, I'm coming," I replied.</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-07-06-screen-rest/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-07-06-screen-rest/</link><title>screen_rest: The Simplest Passive Program to Get Off the Computer</title><description>The program that I've been waiting for, has now come/been made!For the past ... years, my dad has been telling me that after every hour I'm on
the computer, I should commit 15 minutes to doing something else strictly
NOT computer related. I now have finally created a program to help me:
screen_rest.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-06-22-end-of-school/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-06-22-end-of-school/</link><title>The End of School</title><description>So here I am again, at the end of the school year. Well, almost the end - I
still have a public exam and still have to grab my report card, but at least all
the classes are over. With the end of the academic year, I can finally focus
full force on a lot more of my side projects, as well as some of my "online"
courses. As of writing, I am currently enrolled in a Coursera Android
class. The end of school also means that I could spend time honing my formerly
non-existent chess skills. Mind you, I still need to study for the exam, but
after that, I am/will be in full control for 2 months, right up till school
starts again in September.A (programming) project that I am currently working on is a Chip-8
Emulator. I have expanded it to a Chip-8 toolset, and am currently working
on the assembler. (Any feedback or suggestions are welcome.) The going is quite
slow, because of a small amount of procrastination. And studying.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-06-15-cw-peripheral-disappointment/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-06-15-cw-peripheral-disappointment/</link><title>[Writing] Peripheral Disappointment</title><description>Teddy was walking down the lifeless wooden corridor to the pre-trial. It was
paradoxical, really, that the hallway he was walking through glowed with strong
ambient-yellow fluorescent lights; the passage was radiating coldness. He knew
what he was going to do</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-05-30-review-tkrm/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-05-30-review-tkrm/</link><title>[Review] The Kite Runner (Movie) - A Mistake?</title><description>WARNING: The Kite Runner SPOILERS BELOW.The Kite Runner movie by Marc Forster, an adaptation to the book with the same
title by Khaled Hosseini, and a feasible alternative to reading the book (or
SparkNotes). With a $20M budget, this film did quite well in the box office, and
got an average of 6.5/10 on RottenTomatoes. So, was this movie a mistake?</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-05-14-the-road-to-be-good/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-05-14-the-road-to-be-good/</link><title>[Journal] The Road to be Good</title><description>This will be a new kind of post: A journal entry (from my Ink Provoking
Journal). These are some topics about books, poetry, and all that kind of stuff.
It will or will not contain a fair bit of spoilers (if it is about some novel).
This one is based on the book "The Kite Runner". If you haven't read it, read
it, because it is good, and also because there are some suggestive spoilers in
the writing. Well, I'm not going to keep you waiting, so here you are!TOPIC</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-05-03-review-deemo/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-05-03-review-deemo/</link><title>[Review] But I thought it was a Deemo!</title><description>Never left without saying goodbyeDeemo, the rhythm-tapping mobile game, with a unorthodox storyline:</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-04-18-mannerism-deflation/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-04-18-mannerism-deflation/</link><title>Mannerism Deflation</title><description>Having good manners is important to leading a successful social life, and to not
be a sociopath. You say your amounts of "thanks" and "sorry" every single day.
Yet, we don't usually think much about saying it. Have we been so used to saying
these words (pressured by parents) that the words have become the default
reaction to certain scenarios?Everyone's been taught to say "please" and "thank you" by most parents. They
tell you to say "sorry" when you have done something wrong, sometimes when it
isn't even your fault, just to avoid conflicts. This isn't wrong in the
slightest, but when you grow accustomed, and they come out almost literally at
any slip of the tongue, you might not be really meaning what you say. This is
what I mean by "Mannerism Deflation" - the phenomenon of saying "bless you"
and whatnot increasingly, but the value behind the words decrease.</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-04-03-lightning-theory/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-04-03-lightning-theory/</link><title>Basic Lightning Theory</title><description>IntroductionEvery good game needs good visual effects. Here is how to do basic lightning.
This only covers 2D lightning, but you could easily extend this to 3D.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-03-27-how-to-switch-to-new-samsung-phone/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-03-27-how-to-switch-to-new-samsung-phone/</link><title>How to Switch From one Samsung Phone to Another</title><description>Download Samsung Smart Switch Mobile This also works for any android
phone/IOS phone switching to Samsung phone. Download this app for both
devices. For both phones, press "Android to Galaxy", and hold them close
together. For the old phone, check the items that you want to send, then
press "Transfer". If that doesn't transfer, use the "Connect device manually"
option in the menu. This should take a relatively short amount of time.Switch (micro)SD cards Well, duh...</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-03-22-cw-a-close-call/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-03-22-cw-a-close-call/</link><title>[Writing] A Close Call</title><description>I finished up my lunch."Hurry up, Bob, you're late!"</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-03-04-cw-the-old-video/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-03-04-cw-the-old-video/</link><title>[Writing] The Old Video</title><description>"You'd think they'd know better than to ask ME to do it." Bob thought aloud. "If
my dad just passed away, that would be like rubbing salt into a wound, except it
is. But they want to see it, so I'll let it be." Bob opened up his computer and
began traversing through directories, scanning for any pictures, videos that had
his dad (and preferably him) in it and started putting them all into a folder,
in which he would create a video montage in memory of his father. It was lonely
enough in the house after his mother passed away, but now, without his father,
he was completely alone.He finished copying the files into the folder, and clicked on his favourite
video editor. The memories of their past adventures and mishaps flooded through
his mind, but he cleared his head after the program had finished loading. He
began inspecting the photos and videos one by one.</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-23-fun-with-qbasic/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-23-fun-with-qbasic/</link><title>Fun with QBasic</title><description>So I had a rough day with windows (I can no longer use it without safe mode,
would fix later), so I wanted to have some fun, so I went with a qbasic tutorial
and made this colorful thing:</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-07-ncurses-editor-tutorial-04/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-07-ncurses-editor-tutorial-04/</link><title>NCURSES Terminal Text Editor Tutorial Part 4</title><description>Salutations!Just gonna apologize for the weird intros - I'm starting to run out of phrases
to start the intro. Last time we left off, we finished a bunch of
implementations such as the input handler, moving directions, etc. Now, we are
going to finish up everything!</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-04-ncurses-editor-tutorial-03/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-04-ncurses-editor-tutorial-03/</link><title>NCURSES Terminal Text Editor Tutorial Part 3</title><description>Welcome BackLast time we left off, we finished the Buffer class. Here comes the fun stuff:
Doing the functions for the Editor class! What fun! We will start immediately!</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-01-ncurses-editor-tutorial-01/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-01-ncurses-editor-tutorial-01/</link><title>NCURSES Terminal Text Editor Tutorial Part 1</title><description>IntroductionI am using vim right now, and a few days ago, I thought to myself:</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-01-ncurses-editor-tutorial-02/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-02-01-ncurses-editor-tutorial-02/</link><title>NCURSES Terminal Text Editor Tutorial Part 2</title><description>Welcome BackLast time, we finished the basic skeleton, and now it is time to implement some
functions! Let's do some easy ones first.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-01-26-wallclimbing-is-tiring/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-01-26-wallclimbing-is-tiring/</link><title>Wallclimbing is tiring</title><description>Well, what do you know? Wallclimbing is tiring. Our class went wallclimbing
today. My fingers were sore and are still sore from all that gripping. How are
those tiny muscles in your fingers supposed to maintain your grip on a round
hand-hold? A major workout for the whole body, I suppose. It was very fun and
challenging. This was my first time going up a wall that tall (the ones at the
gym don't count), with a guy manning the ropes of course. I should think about
taking up wallclimbing as a hobby.</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-01-20-python-global-variables-vs-classes/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-01-20-python-global-variables-vs-classes/</link><title>Python global variables vs classes</title><description>In programming class, the guys sitting next to me found this amazing thing,
where you could setup a static class, put variables into it, and treat it as a
normal variables, so that in functions, you do not need to call it via global
keyword. Example:</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-01-19-my-way-of-overcoming-procrastination/</guid><link>https://cheuksblog.ca/2015-01-19-my-way-of-overcoming-procrastination/</link><title>My way of Overcoming Procrastination</title><description>Procrastination has become a huge problem in my (high) school career, and
probably will be.  From school projects to homework assignments to studying for
tests, I always had been avoiding it until the very last minutes. I don't know
about you guys, but here are some methods I use to combat procrastination:Make a Day ScheduleI know this sounds really cheesy, but it works. Having a plan of what you
would be doing for the day helps immensely. I write my schedule on the night
before the day I am scheduling. It also helps if you have a guy who could
tell you if you are off track. Make this 'schedule writing' a part of your
habit, and you won't be procrastinating to write the schedule. Write it
regularly once or twice and you're good to go. I recommend writing it on a
small notebook because there are lots of distractions if you write it on
your computer. Unless you don't want to keep a notebook around/don't have
one. Just write a schedule and stick with it.Finish all of your work at workAs a student, I don't like doing homework at home because the opportunity
cost of doing it at home is more significant than doing it at school. That's
why I do it at school. Then you'll have more time at home to do whatever you
like.Have self-controlIf you don't have enough self-control, ask someone to watch over you. ahem
Family &amp; friends ahem. Without sufficient self-control, you may not be
able to do the (2) items listed above.</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>